Guide to the Women of Rice interviews and exhibition records UA 322
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Women of Rice interviews and exhibition records
1988-2014
2012-2014
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Riedel, Brian
UA 322
0.25 Linear Feet 1 box
Correspondence, interview transcripts and materials related to Dr. Linda Driskill's Rice Women's Conference in 1999. The 2012-2013 interviews were conducted by students in two classes of the Introduction to the Study of Women, Gender, and Sexuality, one under Dr. Lora Wildenthal and the other under Dr. Abigail Rosas, in preparation for the 2014 exhibition and symposium at Fondren Library.
Biographical / Historical
The 2014 exhibition and symposium "Women of Rice" were developed by Rosemary Hennessy, Andgela Wren Hall, Linda Driskill, Brian Riedel and the Center for the Study of Women, Gender, and Sexuality, at Rice University. Many faculty and staff participated in the Women of Rice Working Group toward these events. Students in Dr. Lora Wildenthasl's (2012) and Dr. Abigail Rosas (2013) Introduction to Sexuality, Womens and Gender Studies (SWGS) class interviewed women on campus, and excerpts from these interviews were used in the 2014 exhibition at Fondren Library.
Scope and Contents
The 2012-2013 interviews were conducted by students in two classes of the Introduction to the Study of Women, Gender, and Sexuality, one under Dr. Lora Wildenthal and the other under Dr. Abigail Rosas, in preparation for the 2014 exhibition and symposium at Fondren Library.
All of these materials relate to Dr. Linda Driskill's Rice Women's Conference in 1999. Interviews conducted at that time are online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/75565, and are part of Rice University Women's Studies Records, UA 344, Woodson Research Center, Fondren Library, Rice University.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was gathered by Dr. Rosemary Hennessy, Director of the Center for the Study of Women, Gender, and Sexuality, and transferred by Dr. Brian Riedel, Rice University, 2018.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Women--Education; Rice University--History; Women
Document Types
transcripts; photographs; letters (correspondence); notes; reports
Places
Texas
- Series I: Materials for 2014 exhibition
  - Women of Rice Working Group correspondence, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Women of Rice: Our Legacy and Labor" symposium flyer, 2014-03-13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Printed photos of "Women of Rice" exhibition as installed at Fondren Library, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Interviews by Intro to SWGS students, 2012-2013
  - Interview transcripts (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Scope and Contents
    Interviewees with transcripts in this folder include: Bertha Guerra, Facilities Supervisor; Ginny Martin, Fondren Library; Patricia Jones, Property Administrator Accounting Supervisor; Mary Santos, Staff Asst. for Athletics; Nancy Rowe, Grounds Specialist; Venora Frazier, Baker College Coordinator
- Series III: 1999 Women's Conference at Rice documents, 1988-1999
  - Rice Women's Conference 1999: Participant List (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Rice Women: Celebrations, Challenges, Possibilities" event program, 1999-03-05 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rice University Commission on Women (RUCOW) Report of Task Force on Part-Time Employment, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)